platial.com 2009-12-30

# Platial.com

## Updated: January 7, 2008

Platial and Frappr rely on you, our users, for our success. We know that in order for you to use the Platial and Frappr website and services (the “Service”), you have to feel comfortable providing us with personal information about yourself. We respect your privacy and recognize the importance of safeguarding that information.

This Privacy Policy informs you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information received from our users of the Service and of the website located at www.platial.com and www.frappr.com (the “Sites”), and is incorporated into our Terms of Use and Membership Agreement. It may be updated from time to time as our services change and expand. We will notify you of such changes by posting a notice and the new Privacy Policy on the Sites, and your continued use of the Sites will signify your acceptance of these new terms. The most current version of the Privacy Policy can be found at http://www.platial.com/privacy.

**What Information Does Platial Collect?**

_Personally Identifiable Information_  
When you register to use the Service we may collect your Platial membership ID, your login password, your email address, mailing address, telephone number and bank account details. From time to time, in the future, we may offer additional features, services, and promotional opportunities that would require you to submit additional personally identifiable information to participate – for example, if we offer aspects of the Service for a fee we will collect credit card information from you, email address upon registration and various data based on Place inputs. 

_Site Usage Data_  
When you visit the Sites, our computers may automatically collect statistics about your visit. This information does not identify you personally, but rather identifies information about a visit to the Sites. We may monitor statistics such as how many people visit the Sites, the user's IP address, which pages people visit, from which domains our visitors come and which browsers people use. We use these statistics about your visit for aggregation purposes only. These statistics are used to help us improve the performance of the Sites. 

_Cookies_  
Like many websites, we use “cookies” to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies for two purposes. First, we utilize persistent cookies to save your Platial or Frappr membership ID and login password if you have configured your browser to do so for future logins to the Sites and Service. Second, we utilize session cookies to enable certain features of the Sites and Service, to better understand how you interact with the Sites and Service, and to monitor aggregate usage by our users and web traffic routing on the Sites. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you disconnect from the Sites and Service. Aside from your Platial/Frappr membership ID, these cookies do not contain any personally identifiable information. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your browser, by editing its options, to stop accepting cookies or prompt you before accepting a cookie from the sites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Sites or all functionality of the Service. You can learn more about the use of cookies by visiting http://networkadvertising.org or http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie. Third party advertising agencies may place advertisements on the Sites and may also use cookies of their own. 

_Phishing_  
We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, Platial/Frappr membership ID, login password, or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. Identity theft and the practice currently known as "phishing" are of great concern to Platial. Safeguarding information to help protect your from identity theft is our priority. For more information about phishing, you may want to visit the Federal Trade Commission at http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/alerts/phishingalrt.htm.

**How Do We Use The Information We Collect?**

Our primary goal in collecting information from you is to provide you with a smooth and efficient experience while you're using our Sites and Service, and to keep you informed of opportunities available about the Sites and Service. This allows us to provide features that are most likely to meet your needs, and to customize the Service. In addition, we may share information you provide among Platial-related entities worldwide (those entities with whom we share common control).

We may use your email, mailing addresses and phone number to contact you regarding administrative notices, new product and service offerings, including without limitation our Co-Operative Membership Program **platial.com/coopterms** promotions, and communications relevant to your use of the Sites and Service, and to respond to your questions and requests. If you do not wish to receive mail from Platial, you have the ability to stop receiving these mail communications by sending your Platial membership ID, legal name and email address via email to [stop contacting me](mailto:stopcontactingme@platial.com), or via regular mail to Do Not Mail, Platial. If you do not wish to receive email communications from Platial, you have the ability to stop receiving these email communications by sending your Platial membership ID and email address to [unsubscribe](mailto:unsubscribe@platial.com). And, although we do not share your personally identifiable information with our business partners, we may send promotional emails on behalf of those business partners. At the end of any promotional emails you receive from us, you will find instructions to opt out of further similar communications. 

You will receive administrative emails that are related to the primary usage and functionality of the Sites and Service. You may not opt-out of administrative emails.

If you become a member of our Co-Operative Membership Program, we will collect bank account details from you in order to make payments to you in accordance with the terms of the Co-Operative Membership Agreement **platial.com/coopterms**.

Information you provide when registering may be used in the aggregate for demographic statistics and to display appropriate individualized content, advertisements and services. Platial may also use information you provide, including personal and non-identifying information, for internal marketing and development efforts.

From time-to-time we will survey Platial and Frappr members. If you choose to provide personal information in response to a survey, such information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use of and satisfaction with the Sites and Service, and improving our customer service and product and Service offerings. We may also from time to time run promotions, sweepstakes or contests and may enter Platial and Frappr members into such promotions, sweepstakes or contests. If a promotion, sweepstakes or contest has an outside sponsor, the email addresses of Platial and Frappr members may be shared with the sponsor. When necessary to deliver a prize, delivery information about the winner of a promotion, sweepstakes or contest may be shared with a third party.

**Do We Share Your Personal Information With Third Parties, Such As Advertisers, Service Providers, or Consultants?**

We may use third parties to facilitate the Sites and Service, and therefore, may provide some of your information directly to them. In addition, we may employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf, such as analyzing data and processing credit card payments, if applicable. These companies and individuals have access to your information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for any other purpose.  
Platial may disclose your information to government, law enforcement officials, or appropriate authorities, or private parties, as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate, when required by law or under the good-faith belief that such disclosure is necessary, in order to conform to applicable law, comply with legal process served on Platial, to protect the property or interests of Platial, its agents and employees, the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop any fraudulent, illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity. Under such circumstances, Platial may be prohibited by law, court order or other legal process from providing notice of the disclosure, and Platial reserves the right to not provide such notice in its sole discretion. In some cases, the government can compel the disclosure of information about you, and Platial will need to comply, in which case you authorize it to do so. You also consent to Platial disclosing information about you in connection with disputes involving other Platial members, and to actual or potential parties to a lawsuit or action that Platial is or may become involved in, (a) if Platial is required to do so, (b) if Platial reasonably believes that such disclosures will potentially mitigate its liability, or (c) for Platial to enforce its rights.

As its business evolves, Platial may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including information provided by you, in connection with a merger, reorganization, or sale of assets, or in the event of bankruptcy. In such an event, personal and anonymous information may be one of the assets transferred.

Information collected on the Platial and Frappr websites may be stored and processed in any country in which Platial maintains facilities. Consequently, Platial has the right to transfer information outside of your country. For example, if you are registering on any websites controlled by Platial or Platial-related entities located in the European Union, your personally identifiable information must be disclosed to Platial which is outside of the European Union in order to receive the Service. Therefore, you acknowledge and consent to the sharing of your personal information with Platial and Platial-related entities worldwide. 

Platial may share your information with advertisers, marketers and/or event sponsors. 

**Children’s Privacy**

This Sites and Services are not directed to children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [privacy](mailto:privacy@platial.com). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files. 

**Can You View, Correct or Delete Your Personal Information?**

Platial will use reasonable efforts to keep your personal information accurate. We would appreciate your help in ensuring the information you provide to us is accurate and up-to-date. Providing accurate information helps us serve you better. You may easily up-date your personal information through the your splash page. If you wish to completely delete any information after you have submitted information on such fields, then your account may become deactivated. However, if you wish to have your record deleted, please contact us and we will accommodate your request. Our privacy contact is provided below. 

**Is Your Information Secure?**

Platial shall take appropriate organizational and technical measures to protect the information provided to it or collected by it, and shall not retain it any longer than required in order to provide the Services or as required under relevant legislation. 

**Links**

The Sites may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that Platial is not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave the Sites and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information to learn more about their information practices. 

**Contacting Us With Questions or Concerns:**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, you can contact: [privacy](mailto:privacy@platial.com).
